Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

B VijayKumar Chary (1) Featured

Immediate Joiner + Exp: 3.8yrs at Capgemini (3Months Onsite @ Belgium) + Primary skills : Cobol , PL/1 , JCL , VSAM , DB2, CICS + Designation : Associate Consultant + No Location Constraint + Willing to work in shifts + Willing to work as C2H



Current Designation: Associate Consultant Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 8 Month(s)

Current Company: Capgemini Technology Services India

Limited

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Pref. Location: Hyderabad, Pune, Bengaluru / Bangalore Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Associate Consultant, Software Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, Project Management, Defect Tracking, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Debugging, Application

Support, Algorithms, Cobol, JCL, VSAM, Cics, PL1, Db2

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

Worked for 3 years 8 months at Capgemini India Private Limited . This includes

months of onsite experience at Belgium, Europe

Designation : Associate Consultant Domain area : Cobol ,Telon, SQL .

Good Coding Skills.

Has Experience in building queries for doing data validations

Experience in preparing Algorithms, Designing Flow charts, Coding of new programs.

Experience in preparing Test case scenarios , Execution of Test cases , Giving support to other team members on my programs,

Handling critical issues during the Product launch.

Experience in Defect tracking and bug Fixing ,Worked on Debugging tool.

Preparing Status reports

Collaborating with clients and collecting their requirements .

Has good Communication skills and Analytical skills.

Has experience in Documentation work. (MS-Word and MS-Excel)

can give deliverables on time, by sticking to the deadlines.

Work Experience

Capgemini Technology Services India Limited as Associate Consultant Nov 2013 to Jul 2017

Coding of new programs, preparing Test case scenarios, Execution of Test cases, Building queries for doing data validations, preparing Algorithms, Designing Flow charts, Giving support to other team members on my programs, Handling critical issues during the Product launch, Defect tracking and bug Fixing, Worked on Debugging tool, Preparing Status reports, Collaborating with clients and collecting their requirements, good Communication skills and Analytical skills., experience in Documentation work (MS-Word and MS-Excel), I can give deliverables on time by sticking to the deadlines.

Capgemini Technology Services India Limited as Associate Consultant

Nov 2013 to Till Date

Job Profile: Coding of new programs, preparing Test case scenarios, Execution of Test cases, Building queries for doing data validations, preparing Algorithms, Designing Flow charts, Giving support to other team members on my programs, Handling critical issues during the Product launch, Defect tracking and bug Fixing, Worked on Debugging tool, Preparing Status reports, Collaborating with clients and collecting their requirements, good Communication skills and Analytical skills., experience in Documentation work (MS-Word and MS-Excel), I can give deliverables on time by sticking to the deadlines.

Capgemini India Private Limited as Associate Consultant

Nov 2013 to Jul 2017

PROJECT 1: Project Name Standard And Poors:

Role

Team Lead

Client

Euroclear

Team Size

7

Domain

Cobol and SQL

DESCRIPTION OF THE PROJECT:

Standard and poors is a credit rating agency, that publishes financial research and analysis on stocks, bonds and commodities. S&P is considered the largest of the big three credit rating agencies.

European Central bank has changed some regulations criteria. To comply with this regulations, some internal components needed to be changed. Clients will suggest the modifications needed to be made in the components.

Leading a team of 7 Associates from offshore team and responsible for all the offshore deliverables.

Involved in Daily status calls with onsite team, Preparation of Test Plan, Preparing Test Cases, Sending status reports on daily basis

Assigning tasks to the team members

Preparing Algorithms, Coding the changes, Preparing Test cases and documenting the results.

Reviewing deliverables of the associates and Supporting them to resolve issues.

Responsible for all the testing done from offshore, Test case preparation, Test case review, Test execution, Tracking Defects, Tracking issues/Risks, coordinating with onsite team for execution

This is the best project I worked in Euroclear. It gave me a good exposure and recognition among my team members. And Opportunity to work at Onsite.

PROJECT 2: Project Name DTCC:

Role

Developer

Client

Euroclear

Team Size

5

Domain

Cobol and SQL

DESCRIPTION OF THE PROJECT:

The Depository Trust and Clearing Corporation is an American post-Trade financial services company providing clearing and settlement services to the financial markets. It performs the exchange of

securities on behalf of buyers and sellers and functions as a central securities depository by providing central custody of securities

Some changes are made in the Central Database, Which impacted many components. Project requirements are to be collected from the client. Analyse the changes to be made in the components. Design the algorithm, coding and testing the code accordingly.

Roles and Responsibilities:

Making code related changes in the components.

Preparation of High and Low level design document and Unit test cases.

Testing SQL queries.

Was part o defect Triage and was responsible for the major defect closures.

Interaction with the Testing team to resolve defects.

Daily Task Progress mail to Onsite Team/Client.

Capgemini as Associate Consultant

Nov 2013 to Jul 2017

Coding of new programs, preparing Test case scenarios, Execution of Test cases, Building queries for doing data validations, preparing Algorithms, Designing Flow charts, Giving support to other team members on my programs, Handling critical issues during the Product launch, Defect tracking and bug Fixing, Worked on Debugging tool, Preparing Status reports, Collaborating with clients and collecting their requirements, good Communication skills and Analytical skills., experience in Documentation work (MS-Word and MS-Excel), I can give deliverables on time by sticking to the deadlines.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from SNIST JNTUH, Telangana in 2013

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Diploma in Computer Science

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Windows 2010, Unix, SQL , MS-Access			0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
MS- PowerPoint , MS-Excel, MS-Word			
Html; CSS; Javascript; C; C++, Java			0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Mainframes; COBOL; JCL; PL/1; SQL;			3 Year(s) 8 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Telugu				

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time